A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12 FA284
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
1930-1952
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA284
19 Cubic Feet 50 boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement note
This series is arranged in 3 subseries:
Subseries 1 General Files
Subseries 2 State Files
Subseries 3 Public Health Fellowships
The fellowship files contained in this series are arranged alphabetically, first by state and then by last name of recipient.
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Scope and Contents note
The Commonwealth Fund announced in late 1929 a new project that began operation on January 1, 1930, and promoted rural health and medical service in the United States. The new program, instead of emphasizing child care, comprised all health services in rural communities. Initially the project was limited to two states, Tennessee (1930-1945) and Massachusetts (1930-1945), and to two counties or districts in each state. Later the program was also active in Mississippi (1931-1947), Oklahoma (1938-1949), Alabama (1938-1942), Arkansas (1945-1947), California, Florida (1945-1947), Kentucky (1945-1947), Louisiana (1946), Maine, New Jersey, Ohio, Virginia, and Washington. Dr. William J. French, the first director of the CF's child-health demonstration in Fargo, North Dakota, and former head of the CF's Austrian Program, was named director. French resigned his post on April 4, 1931, and on May 15, 1931, Clarence L. Scamman became the new director of the Division.
The goals set forth were to create field units to promote rural health service and develop well-rounded health services. The work was conducted with the cooperation of the states' health departments. The project also included the establishment of scholarships for graduate study by rural physicians and for nurses and teachers who wished to study methods of health education, and scholarships or loan funds for medical students who would undertake rural practice. The fellowship files contained in this series cover the years 1931 to 1951. A complete alphabetical card file index to the fellowships is available. The use of files may be restricted if they contain information of a personal or sensitive nature.
Medical research; Medicine, Rural; Legal research; Medical education; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Mental health; War relief; New York (State); Public health; Public welfare; United States; Child welfare; Child psychology; Child mental health; New York (N.Y.); Legal issues; Law; Hygiene; Education, Rural
- General Files, 1921-1953; 1
  Arrangement note
  This subseries is sub-divided into 5 subseries:
  Subseries 1 American Public Health Association
  Subseries 2 Program Files
  Subseries 3 Miscellaneous Projects and Grants
  Subseries 4 Special Studies
  Subseries 5 United States Public Health Service Files
  - American Public Health Association, 1
    - Accreditation of Schools of Public Health - Correspondence and Reports, 1945 April 24-1953 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - State Health Studies - Correspondence and Reports, 1947 October 21-1951 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Subcommittee on Grading - Correspondence and Reports, April 14, 1948-May 9, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Subcommittee on Opportunities in Statistical Work - Correspondence, January 9, 1947-July 29, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Subcommittee on State and Local Health Administration - Correspondence, Minutes and Reports, 1929 November 29-1939 September 1; 1948 January 2-November 16 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Program Files, 2
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9-16)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 17-27)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Athens, Georgia) - General Correspondence, August 28, 1929-August 23, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Fargo, North Dakota) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1927 January 1-1942 July 2 (Box 2, Folder 29-31)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, January 1, 1926-June 30, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1928 August 23-1938 January 28 (Box 3, Folder 33-37)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Annual Report, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Charter and Program Development, April 22, 1930-August 11, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1929 June 25-1949 October 26 (Box 3, Folder 40-43)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Report of Public Health Activities, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Statistical Summary of Public Health Activities, 1921-1950 (Box 3, Folder 45-46)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Study of Public Health Activities, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Summary of Public Health Activities, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Surveys of Public Health Activities, 1923-1928 and 1923-1929; 1927 (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Surveys of Public Health Activities, 1932 and 1934; 1942 and 1944 (Box 4, Folder 51-52)
    - Correspondence, 1930 October 30-1951 October 8 (Box 4, Folder 53-59)
    - Field Reports, 1933 January-1937 October; 1943 November-1948 December (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
    - Memoranda - Sheehan, 1947 September 8,-1948 June 21 (Box 4, Folder 62-63)
    - Memoranda - Smith, 1930 December 18-1939 December 5 (Box 4, Folder 64-68)
    - Memoranda - Smith, 1940 January 25-1947 August 20 (Box 5, Folder 69-72)
    - Memoranda and Reports, 1930 June 1-1951 March 31 (Box 5, Folder 73-79)
    - Program Budgets and Memoranda, 1948 January 1-1952 June 30 (Box 5, Folder 80-81)
    - Program Outline and Memoranda, 1952 January 1-1952 June 30 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Roster - Advisory Committee on Public Health, 1930-1946 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Grants, 3
    - Albany Medical College - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 23, 1948-November 4, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Bingham Fund Associates - General Files, October 22, 1931-November 13, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Columbia University School of Public Health - Memoranda and Correspondence, 1945 July 9-1953 December 16 (Box 6, Folder 86-87)
    - Conference of Deans of Schools of Public Health - Correspondence, November 12, 1948-October 19, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Health Education - University of Tennessee - Report, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 89-90)
    - Health Education - University of Tennessee - Seminar Material, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 91-92)
    - Mental Health Institute - Conference Material, April 26, 1949-May 7, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Mental Health Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1948 November 5-1949 June 23 (Box 6, Folder 94-98)
    - Undergraduate Fellowship Program - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1939 September 22-1941 June 17 (Box 7, Folder 99-100)
    - University of Michigan School of Public Health - Correspondence, April 5, 1950-May 5, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - University of North Carolina - Correspondence and Program Outline, 1949 September 8-1951 April 14 (Box 7, Folder 102-103)
    - University of Toronto - Correspondence and Memoranda, March 23, 1948-November 30, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Vanderbilt University Medical School Scholarships and Internships - Correspondence and Reports, 1932 January 8-1934 December 27 (Box 7, Folder 105-108)
    - Yale University - Correspondence and Reports, October 1, 1948-January 13, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Special Studies, 4
    - Blood Study (Pike County Mississippi) - Memoranda and Reports, April 28, 1936-September 30, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Conference of State and Provincial Health Authorities (Committee on Records) - Memoranda and Correspondence, April 9, 1936-June 14, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Conference of State and Provincial Health Authorities (Committee on Records) - Report, February-July 1941 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Conference of State and Provincial Health Authorities (Committee on Records) - Report, July 2, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Field Unit Study (Tennessee) - Memoranda and Reports, January 26, 1937-June 24, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Maternity Study (County Health Departments) - Reports and Correspondence, 1944 August 25-1950 August 1 (Box 8, Folder 115-116)
    - Maternity Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Correspondence and Reports, 1933 September 19-1942 December 29 (Box 8, Folder 117-120)
    - Maternity Study (Jones County Mississippi) - Correspondence and Reports, June 25, 1940-May 12, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Maternity Study (Pike County Mississippi) - Correspondence and Memoranda, December 2, 1935-September 18, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - Maternity Study (Pike County Mississippi) - Reports, 1937-1945 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - New York City Health Department Records - Reports, January 26, 1948-April 6, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Nursing Study (Southern Berkshire Health District, Massachusetts) - Memoranda and Reports, 1933 November 28-1935 November 18 (Box 8, Folder 125-126)
    - Record Unit and Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, March 8, 1935-December 21, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Rutherford County Tennessee - Statistical Studies, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 128-129)
    - Rutherford County Tennessee - Study on Health Services for Mothers and Young Children in Rural Areas, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - School Health Services (Tennessee) - Correspondence Reports and Memoranda, 1936 October 6-1941 December 3 (Box 9, Folder 131-133)
    - Syphilis Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Memoranda and Reports, 1935 June 11-1944 January 14 (Box 9, Folder 134-136)
    - Syphilis Study (Tennessee and Mississippi) - Memoranda and Reports, January 6, 1943-December 5, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1946 February 26-1951 May 17 (Box 9, Folder 138-143)
    - Typhoid Fever Study (Rutherford County Mississippi) - Correspondence and Reports, February 1, 1932-October 29, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 144)
  - United States Public Health Service Files, 5
    - Federal Security Agency - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1948 February 11-1951 May 14 (Box 10, Folder 145-146)
    - General Correspondence and Memoranda, April 25, 1945-December 20, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 147)
- State Files, 1921-1962; 2
  - Alabama - Annual Reports, 1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 148-150)
  - Alabama - Budget Correspondence, 1938 February 21-1942 January 8 (Box 10, Folder 151-152)
  - Alabama - Field Trip Reports, 1937 July-1941 May (Box 10, Folder 153-154)
  - Alabama - Financial Correspondence, August 22, 1938-August 18, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 155)
  - Alabama - General Correspondence, 1928 March 1-1942 May 20 (Box 10, Folder 156-157)
  - Arkansas - Budget and Financial Correspondence, December 15, 1944-June 30, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - Arkansas - General Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, April 2, 1936-December 19, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 159)
  - California - General Correspondence and Field Report, December 2, 1943-July 11, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 160)
  - District of Columbia - General Correspondence and Field Reports, January 29, 1936-June 9, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 161)
  - Florida - Budget and Budget Correspondence, 1944 December 15-1951 July 2 (Box 11, Folder 162-163)
  - Florida - Field Technical Staff Reports, 1947-1950 (Box 11, Folder 164-165)
  - Florida - Field Training Center - Correspondence, 1947 January 8-1954 July 7 (Box 11, Folder 166-168)
  - Florida - Field Training Center - Reports, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 169-172)
  - Florida - Field Trip Reports, 1942 January 16-1950 November 22 (Box 11, Folder 173-174)
  - Florida - Financial Correspondence, 1946 January 8-1947 December 22 (Box 11, Folder 175-176)
  - Florida - Financial Correspondence, January 9, 1948-February 20, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 177)
  - Florida - General Correspondence, 1944 January 13-1950 October 14 (Box 12, Folder 178-182)
  - Kentucky - Barren County Reports, 1931-1937 (Box 12, Folder 183-186)
  - Kentucky - Budget and Financial Correspondence, December 15, 1944-March 19, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 187)
  - Kentucky - Field Trip Reports, May 2, 1935-June 4, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 188)
  - Kentucky - General Correspondence, January 13, 1944-July 30, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 189)
  - Kentucky - Vital Statistics Reports, January 8, 1945-March 5, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 190)
  - Louisiana - Budget and Budget Correspondence, September 29, 1945-January 18, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 191)
  - Louisiana - Field Training Center Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 192)
  - Louisiana - Field Training Center Reports, 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 193)
  - Louisiana - Field Trip Reports, September 7, 1943-December 13, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 194)
  - Louisiana - Financial Correspondence, February 27, 1946-September 12, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 195)
  - Louisiana - General Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1935 August 6-1951 November 29 (Box 13, Folder 196-198)
  - Louisiana - Report to the Commonwealth Fund Concerning Progress in the Louisiana Public Health Field Training Program 1945 to 1950 (Author: Dr. Ben Freedman), 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 199-200)
  - Maine - Memoranda, Field and Status Reports, 1931 November 9-1937 June 15 (Box 13, Folder 201-202)
  - Maine - Statistical Summaries, 1928-1932 (Box 13, Folder 203)
  - Massachusetts - Applications to Enter District Health Unit, October-December 1930 (Box 13, Folder 204)
  - Massachusetts - Barnstable County Reports, September 1932 (Box 13, Folder 205)
  - Massachusetts - Budget and Budget Correspondence, August 12, 1930-December 14, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 206)
  - Massachusetts - Budget and Budget Correspondence, 1932 January 5-1945 July 3 (Box 14, Folder 207-209)
  - Massachusetts - Cytologic Project - Correspondence and Reports, 1947 October 16-1951 November 30 (Box 14, Folder 210-211)
  - Massachusetts - Division of Laboratories- Reports, June 1943-December 1945 (Box 14, Folder 212)
  - Massachusetts - Field Unit Reports, 1931-1936 (Box 14, Folder 213)
  - Massachusetts - General Correspondence and Reports, 1929 December 4-1946 April 25 (Box 14, Folder 214-218)
  - Massachusetts - Harvard Correspondence and Reports, 1929 December 5-1932 December 30 (Box 14, Folder 219-220)
  - Massachusetts - Harvard Correspondence and Reports, 1933 January 20-1949 July 2 (Box 15, Folder 221-224)
  - Massachusetts - Nashoba Correspondence and Reports, 1931 February 13-1958 June 16 (Box 15, Folder 225-232)
  - Massachusetts - Nashoba Health Center Building - Correspondence, December 18, 1935-May 7, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 233)
  - Massachusetts - Nashoba Survey of Health Activities, 1930-1932 (Box 15, Folder 234-236)
  - Massachusetts - Nashoba Survey of Health Activities, 1933-1935 (Box 16, Folder 237-238)
  - Massachusetts - Requisitions and Financial Correspondence, 1930 October 24-1946 January 28 (Box 16, Folder 239-245)
  - Massachusetts - Southern Berkshire Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1930 November 12-1934 May 18 (Box 16, Folder 246-249)
  - Massachusetts - Southern Berkshire Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1934 July 9-1939 March 27 (Box 17, Folder 250-254)
  - Massachusetts - Southern Berkshire Survey of Health Activities, 1929-1935; 1938 (Box 17, Folder 255-260)
  - Massachusetts - Tuberculosis Unit - Final Report, October 1, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 261)
  - Massachusetts - Tuberculosis Unit - Reports, April 1936-December 1939 (Box 17, Folder 262)
  - Massachusetts - Tufts University - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1929 December 5-1936 December 18 (Box 17, Folder 263-264)
  - Massachusetts - Tufts University - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1937 February 2-1945 August 23 (Box 18, Folder 265-266)
  - Massachusetts - Undergraduate Scholarships, September 28, 1933-September 11, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 267)
  - Mississippi - Budgets and Budget Correspondence, 1931 March 18-1946 December 30 (Box 18, Folder 268-278)
  - Mississippi - Budgets and Budget Correspondence, January 10, 1947-June 16, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 279)
  - Mississippi - Clerical Training Program - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, June 23, 1942-August 18, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 280)
  - Mississippi - Epidemiological Unit - Correspondence and Reports, 1932 December 15-1942 February 5 (Box 19, Folder 281-285)
  - Mississippi - Extension Education Program - Correspondence, 1936 July 8-1943 June 28 (Box 19, Folder 286-288)
  - Mississippi - Field Trip Reports, 1930 May 15-1947 October 4 (Box 19, Folder 289-291)
  - Mississippi - Field Unit Annual Report, July 1, 1940-June 30, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 292)
  - Mississippi - Field Unit Quarterly Reports, 1931 (Box 19, Folder 293)
  - Mississippi - Field Unit Quarterly Reports, 1932-1938 (Box 20, Folder 294-298)
  - Mississippi - Field Unit Report, January 1, 1931-June 30, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 299)
  - Mississippi - Field Unit Semiannual Reports, 1939-1946 (Box 20, Folder 300-302)
  - Mississippi - Financial Correspondence, 1931 December 15-1943 November 24 (Box 20, Folder 303-307)
  - Mississippi - Financial Correspondence, 1944 February 26-1950 September 22 (Box 21, Folder 308-310)
  - Mississippi - General Correspondence and Reports, 1929 December 4-1960 February 18 (Box 21, Folder 311-317)
  - Mississippi - Jones County - Correspondence and Reports, 1935 November 9-1949 June 21 (Box 21, Folder 318-320)
  - Mississippi - Jones County - Health Center Correspondence, January 6, 1942-August 31, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 321)
  - Mississippi - Jones County - Reports, 1938-1942; 1945 and 1947 (Box 22, Folder 322-324)
  - Mississippi - Jones County - Seven Year Review, 1937-1943 (Box 22, Folder 325)
  - Mississippi - Jones County - Statistical Summaries, 1921-1950 (Box 22, Folder 326)
  - Mississippi - Laboratory Reports, 1942 January 1-1947 June 30 (Box 22, Folder 327-328)
  - Mississippi - Lauderdale County - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1931 June 5-1948 June 30 (Box 22, Folder 329-331)
  - Mississippi - Lauderdale County - Health Center Correspondence, May 21, 1937-October 17, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 332)
  - Mississippi - Lauderdale County - Reports, 1930-1935; 1937; 1939-1940; 1942 (Box 22, Folder 333-336)
  - Mississippi - Lauderdale County - Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 337-338)
  - Mississippi - Lauderdale County - Statistical Summaries, 1921-1950 (Box 23, Folder 339)
  - Mississippi - Lauderdale County - Study of Maternal Hygiene Services, 1931-1939 (Box 23, Folder 340)
  - Mississippi - Lee County - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, March 10, 1932-February 10, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 341)
  - Mississippi - Pike County - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1931 March 19-1949 June 21 (Box 23, Folder 342-344)
  - Mississippi - Pike County - Health Center Correspondence, December 16, 1936-July 20, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 345)
  - Mississippi - Pike County - Reports, 1930-1935; 1938-1940; 1942; 1944; 1946 (Box 23, Folder 346-352)
  - Mississippi - Pike County - Statistical Summaries, 1921-1950 (Box 23, Folder 353)
  - Mississippi - Pike County - Survey of Health Activities, 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 354)
  - Mississippi - Public Health Fellowships - Correspondence and Applications, October 1, 1943-March 6, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 355)
  - Mississippi - Statistical Service - Correspondence and Reports, 1943 October 4-1953 January 20 (Box 24, Folder 356-359)
  - Mississippi - Statistical Summaries, 1921-1945 (Box 24, Folder 360)
  - Mississippi - Tulane University - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1927 April 20-1949 October 26 (Box 24, Folder 361-369)
  - Mississippi - Tulane University - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, 1949 November 1-1954 September 21 (Box 25, Folder 370-372)
  - Mississippi - Tulane University - Reprints, March 1951-February 1953 (Box 25, Folder 373)
  - New Jersey - Evaluation Study - Annual Report, September 1, 1950-August 1, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 374)
  - New Jersey - Evaluation Study - Final Report, September 1953 (Box 25, Folder 375)
  - New Jersey - Field Unit - General and Financial Correspondence, Reports, 1951 January 9-1955 December 7 (Box 25, Folder 376-378)
  - New Jersey - General Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, 1947 July 11-1950 December 15 (Box 25, Folder 379-380)
  - New Jersey - Miscellaneous Brochures and Reprints, 1951-1953 (Box 25, Folder 381)
  - Ohio - Reports of Public Health Activities, 1930 and 1932 (Box 25, Folder 382)
  - Oklahoma - Ada - Correspondence and Reports, February 27, 1937-April 28, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 383)
  - Oklahoma - Budgets and Budget Correspondence, 1938 April 15-1949 February 8 (Box 26, Folder 384-388)
  - Oklahoma - Clerical Training - Correspondence and Reports, February 1, 1944-April 1, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 389)
  - Oklahoma - Division of Laboratories - Annual Reports, June 30, 1941 to July 1, 1942; July 1, 1945 to June 30, 1946; and February 1948 (Box 26, Folder 390)
  - Oklahoma - Field Unit Annual Reports, 1944-1947 (Box 26, Folder 391-392)
  - Oklahoma - Field Unit Semi-annual Reports, 1939-1943 (Box 26, Folder 393-395)
  - Oklahoma - Financial Correspondence, September 15, 1938-August 18, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 396)
  - Oklahoma - Financial Correspondence, 1942 January 21-1949 March 3 (Box 27, Folder 397-400)
  - Oklahoma - General Correspondence and Reports, 1937 April 20-1951 October 22 (Box 27, Folder 401-407)
  - Oklahoma - Kay County - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1942 February 12-1943 December 23 (Box 27, Folder 408-413)
  - Oklahoma - Kay County - Evaluation Schedules, 1948-1949 and 1952 (Box 28, Folder 414)
  - Oklahoma - Kay County - Health Center Correspondence and Reports, 1949 June 22-1955 November 2 (Box 28, Folder 415-418)
  - Oklahoma - Kay County - Reports, 1943-1946; 1948 (Box 28, Folder 419-420)
  - Oklahoma - Kay County - Statistical Summaries, 1943-1948 (Box 28, Folder 421)
  - Oklahoma - Seminole City Health Center - Correspondence, December 12, 1947-May 5, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 422)
  - Oklahoma - Seminole County - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1938 June 29-1941 November 29 (Box 28, Folder 423-424)
  - Oklahoma - Seminole County - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1942 January 22-1949 July 6 (Box 29, Folder 425-426)
  - Oklahoma - Seminole County - Health Center Correspondence, 1947 April 24-1952 January 9 (Box 29, Folder 427-430)
  - Oklahoma - Seminole County - Reports, 1938-1943; 1945 (Box 29, Folder 431-433)
  - Oklahoma - Seminole County - Statistical Summaries, 1941-1949 (Box 29, Folder 434)